<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Repost on Loïc M. Divad</title><link>https://blog.loicmdivad.com/tags/repost/</link><description>Recent content in Repost on Loïc M. Divad</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.loicmdivad.com/tags/repost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Repost 🔃 Kafka Streams, co-partitioning requirements illustrated</title><link>https://blog.loicmdivad.com/posts/2020/06/repost-kafka-streams-co-partitioning-requirements-illustrated/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.loicmdivad.com/posts/2020/06/repost-kafka-streams-co-partitioning-requirements-illustrated/</guid><description>Back in 2020, I wrote an article about data exchange between Kafka Streams instances. I was not working with Kafka Stream at a specific time. But my head was full of many ideas I wanted to put on paper after using the Kafka Streams library for quite a while. The way joins happen was one of those ideas.</description></item><item><title>Repost 🔃 Kafka Streams: a road to Autoscaling via Kubernetes</title><link>https://blog.loicmdivad.com/posts/2019/04/repost-kafka-streams-a-road-to-autoscaling-via-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 18:00:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.loicmdivad.com/posts/2019/04/repost-kafka-streams-a-road-to-autoscaling-via-kubernetes/</guid><description>There are many reasons for working on community contributions such as a blog post, a demo, or a talk. Sometimes, you produce those contributions to share something that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned at work. But sometimes, the contribution itself can be a way to learn and experiment something new. I was in the second case when I worked on the article Kafka Streams: a road to Autoscaling via Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>Repost 🔃 Apache Kudu: the New Bigdata Antelope</title><link>https://blog.loicmdivad.com/posts/2017/04/repost-apache-kudu-the-new-bigdata-antelope/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.loicmdivad.com/posts/2017/04/repost-apache-kudu-the-new-bigdata-antelope/</guid><description>Software Engineers frequently engage themself into new learning paths. We keep learning skills related to our field such as programming languages; libraries or even how new data systems work. This idea is one of the 4 company values of @PubSapientEng, and they named it: Sharing Knowledge. Why &amp;ldquo;sharing&amp;rdquo;? Besides the idea to keep up with tech, it&amp;rsquo;s a good way to extends your skills and get new perspectives on the job you do every day.</description></item></channel></rss>